Ben Kane

benkane11@gmail.com • 707-478-9087 • github.com/bkane11
145 Frisbie Street, Oakland, CA 94611

Mr. Kane is a GIS and application developer with 10 years of experience managing large datasets, increasing efficiency in data creation and analysis pipelines, and developing interactive visualizations. Ben has frequently worked on all stages of data management and application development projects, including scope development, development of codebase, version control, maintenance and refactoring, project management, training, and outreach. Mr. Kane has special expertise with deployment and management of enterprise GIS systems including ArcGIS for Server and Portal for ArcGIS, as well as database administration, and web application server architectures in Windows and Linux environments. Mr. Kane currently leads a large regional team of GIS technical experts, including analysts, cartographers, programmers, database, web and software application developers. He draws on his depth of experience and diverse skill set to provide technical support and guidance, as well as to maintain a robust quality assurance program, resulting in increased productivity, quality and consistency of products produced by his teams.

EDUCATION

B.A. Humanities, **2005.** The New College of California.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AECOM, Oakland, CA (2015 – Present)

Application Developer / GIS and Data Management Services Department Manager
Led development team in all aspects of application design and development on multiple large
projects. Responsible for installation and management of multiple instances of server
infrastructure for use by department staff on Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Google Cloud Compute,
and local intranet servers, including: ArcGIS for Server and Portal for ArcGIS; database servers:
SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Redis; and web application servers and components
such as ExpressJS, Restify, IIS, and NGINX. Administered GitHub organization account and 40
repositories used by team of 18 GIS developers and technicians for application development,
version control, issue tracking, and task assignment/management. Developed modular python
tools to automate diverse workflows.

URS Corporation, Oakland, CA (2013 - 2014)

Senior GIS Developer / Full Stack Developer

Designed, developed and maintained multiple applications for data creation, editing and visualization, asset management, workforce management, and task assignment. Installed and managed multiple ArcGIS for Server instances, SQL Server and PostgreSQL database servers, and web application servers on Amazon EC2, Google Cloud Compute, and local intranet servers. Developed scripts and tools (python, shell, bash, SQL, NodeJS) to automate data management, analysis, and display workflows. Implemented utilization of GitHub to improve collaboration and development efforts.

Huxley Spatial Institute, Western Washington University (2011 – 2013)

Web Application Developer and GIS Specialist

Collaborated in installation and management of ArcGIS for Server and PostgreSQL for use by students, faculty and staff of the Huxley Spatial Institute, and to serve web services for consumption by web applications. Participated in development of multiple web applications. Including:

- Avalanche Danger Map for the Northwest Weather and Avalanche Center and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration - Designed and developed map-based visualization tool of daily updated avalanche danger forecasts. Created UI, APIs, and processes to collect and display user submitted reports of avalanche incidents and snowpack conditions.
- WWU Campus Map for Western Washington University Created campus map and integrated into WWU website.

Huxley College of the Environment, Western Washington University (2012)

Instructor: GIS for International Environmental Research Experience

Led coursework in GIS and cartography: techniques, standards and best practices. Developed web application to facilitate data collection by researchers and public users. Maintained GIS system infrastructure to support student coursework.

The Resilience Institute, Huxley College of the Environment, Western Washington University (2011)

GIS Specialist and Web Application Developer

Collaborated with installation of ArcGIS for Server and PostgreSQL installation. Developed geospatial hazard risk assessment and communication web applications. Including:

 Washington Seismic Hazards Catalog for Washington Department of Natural Resources -Designed and built map-based communication of state-wide HAZUS based seismic hazards assessment.

Swallow Valley Farm, Valley Ford, CA (2007 – 2010)

GIS Technician

Developed and populated GIS system for asset management and land use planning. GPS field data collection and validation. Conducted analysis and map production to support grazing planning, habitat restoration, environmental remediation, infrastructure development and site selection.

WORK EXAMPLES

Perris Dam Remediation Program Dashboard - dwr-perris.com. Dashboard for construction management and QA/QC. Integrated with project Sharepoint site for collaboration and data visualization via tabular, mapping, and charting components.

Toxic Trends Mapper - toxictrends.org. Interactive web map to represent and explore the chronic health relative risk to communities from toxic chemical industrial air releases and how those potential risks might change over time .

DWR Levee Evaluation Program - dwr-lep.com. Geospatial portal for accessing multi-year levee condition evaluations and reports.

SKILLS

